[{"id": "5f9f47abaf848b908361b877", "question": "What was the first feature length animated film ever released?", "answer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ec", "question": "What is the astronomical term for three celestial bodies aligning?", "answer": "Syzygy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c704", "question": "What is the only chemical element whose name is only three letters long?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991d", "question": "In \"Legally Blonde\", what magazine does Elle Woods refer to as \"the Bible\"?", "answer": "Cosmopolitan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede0ee6ce05a3942286dbe", "question": "What is the name of the serial killer in the film \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdf", "question": "What is the last name of the founder of the Papa John's pizza chain?", "answer": "Schnatter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f7", "question": "Which US state capital is both the oldest and the highest in the country?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a2", "question": "What is an EKG?", "answer": "An electrocardiogram", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa54bdc73aa70ea0b70b1e", "question": "Which country (and it's territories) cover the most time zones?", "answer": "France and its eight territories cover 12 time zones.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339528", "question": "Who directed the 1990 movie \"La Femme Nikita\"?", "answer": "Luc Besson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f8", "question": "What Olympic field event's two main styles are the glide and the spin?", "answer": "Shot put's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a614", "question": "What is the capital of Nigeria?", "answer": "Abuja", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b532", "question": "What does a spermologer collect?", "answer": "Trivia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36e5c0ada16518afdc044", "question": "What temperature should you not exceed when melting chocolate?", "answer": "120 F or 49 C", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76697eec85e375820b284", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic was known as the \"Bread Basket of the Empire\"?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394eb", "question": "What is the name of the Green Hornet's car?", "answer": "Black Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b60", "question": "What 1970's TV series was revived in 2007 with Michelle Ryan in the title role?", "answer": "Bionic Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff513ceff04d658268c92df", "question": "In which battle did Chinese general Zhang Hongfan destroy the last fleet of the Southern Song Dynasty?", "answer": "The Battle of Yamen occurred on March 19, 1279, near present-day Xinhui County, Guangdong Province.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b699175e762b54eb9be9419", "question": "What decade saw the popularization of the Charleston dance?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31a", "question": "Who provided the original voice for the character of Tigger?", "answer": "Paul Winchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a30", "question": "What athlete's late-night talk show was cancelled after only 8 weeks, in 1998?", "answer": "Magic Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10f", "question": "At what Ohio university were four students shot to death during a 1970 anti-war demonstration?", "answer": "Kent State", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd9", "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4447ff048f679a45ab8c", "question": "What is the anti-matter equivalent of an electron?", "answer": "Positron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc3", "question": "According to the KFC ads, how many herbs and spices are in Colonel's secret recipe?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe655bcae7e414034b5aeb9", "question": "Mausoleum is a word derived from what ancient ruler?", "answer": "Mausolus, ruler of the ancient Anatolian kingdom of Caria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cc4f877e98cb97778a22", "question": "What is the capital city of the U.S. Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Charlotte Amalie", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78a", "question": "What is the chemical formula for ozone?", "answer": "O3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd8", "question": "Who first became president of France in 1995?", "answer": "Jacques Chirac", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a4", "question": "What Pacific island chain is named for Philip IV's Austrian queen?", "answer": "The Marianas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b5d8e662d71a53650fff", "question": "Young protagonist Pecola appears in what Toni Morrison novel?", "answer": "\"The Bluest Eye\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c197", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc8ceec223966ae8f8893", "question": "What term is used in describing a situation where a golfer scores 8 on a hole?", "answer": "\"Snowman\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde49fec6c6b019850c9a71", "question": "Which two nations fought for control of North America in the French and Indian War?", "answer": "France and England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8e", "question": "In Botticelli's \"The Birth of Venus\", what is Venus standing on as she rides to shore?", "answer": "A seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590720f53745b36be73039f4", "question": "Who played the role of Kris Kringle in the 1994 film \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "Richard Attenborough", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f6", "question": "If \"feline\" is used to describe cat-like, what word describes bear-like?", "answer": "Ursine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a942", "question": "At what Seward Peninsula city does the Iditarod end?", "answer": "Nome, Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c121", "question": "What kind of birds would you find in a gaggle?", "answer": "Geese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a101", "question": "Directed by Milos Foreman, which film won the Oscar for Best Picture in 1976?", "answer": "One Flew Over The Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908d", "question": "Which Roman God was the equivalent of the Greek God Dionysus?", "answer": "Bacchus, Liber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb3229e368446ca7bd6841", "question": "Which chemical element has the highest boiling point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb601b5dad637d903c8829", "question": "Which city in the U.S. is home to the National Mustard Museum?", "answer": "Middleton, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d7", "question": "What is the handicap of a \"scratch\" golfer?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1f341145fb29466707399", "question": "What candy bar originally came in three pieces and had three different flavors?", "answer": "3 Musketeers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab86", "question": "Where is the lowest elevation in the US?", "answer": "Death Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59524316736d4be723796b66", "question": "Which \"Doctor Who\" actor was the voice of \"Spotty\" from the Welsh cartoon \"SuperTed\"?", "answer": "Jon Pertwee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96c", "question": "What is an onychophagist?", "answer": "A nail biter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b40906d333868d34d6de", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e2", "question": "What fruit comes in Redhaven and Harmony variety?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a900", "question": "What American street is best known for its eight switchbacks between Hyde and Leavenworth?", "answer": "Lombard Street", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5963724f967692ea851899be", "question": "A jellyfish is made up of 95% of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f0", "question": "In which hemisphere is the Tropic of Cancer located?", "answer": "Northern", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c9af0775fa611bce67ee", "question": "What\u2019s the main difference between a bay and bow window?", "answer": "Number of sections -- Bay windows usually have three sections while bow windows have anywhere from four to six.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede2096ce05a3942286dcb", "question": "What does Seymour have to feed his plant in \"Little Shop Of Horrors\"?", "answer": "Human blood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6699da5bfecdd737e087d", "question": "Why was the Michelin Guide created?", "answer": "To increase the demand for tires", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b052", "question": "Former Yugoslavian leader Josip Broz was also known by what other name?", "answer": "Tito", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30c", "question": "Who uttered the line \"There is no Soviet domination of Eastern Europe\" during a debate?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bb", "question": "What was Robert De Niro's nickname in the movie \"Casino\"?", "answer": "Ace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339532", "question": "What show featured the five orphaned Salinger siblings?", "answer": "Party of Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e7b6ce05a3942286e34", "question": "Whose 2018 LP is titled \"Beautiful People Will Ruin Your Life\"?", "answer": "The Wombats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b072", "question": "Approximately how long did the Pony Express run?", "answer": "18 months", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e03", "question": "What occupation is shared by TV protagonists Sean McNamara and Christian Troy?", "answer": "Plastic surgeon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590089dccf842fa4c4ba968c", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b68", "question": "On what cartoon do the main characters live in the fictional town of Bikini Bottom?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2e", "question": "What U.S. states were once independent republics?", "answer": "Texas and Hawaii", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a93", "question": "Which river did Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn sail down?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edc", "question": "What position was first held by Caesar Augustus?", "answer": "Emperor of Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a309", "question": "Who played the role of Karen on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Natascha McElhone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa6", "question": "In 1987, what song was the first in Spanish to top the US charts?", "answer": "La Bamba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f7", "question": "What is the name of Nintendo's first video game console?", "answer": "Color TV Game", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd667a0a5bfecdd737e086b", "question": "What condition is singultus better known as?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339632", "question": "In the 1995 movie \"Babe\", what Christmas carol does Babe sing?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a758", "question": "The island of Martha's Vineyard is located in what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede01f6ce05a3942286db6", "question": "Which character proclaimed these words: \"Salvation lies within\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Warden Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd9de7e83c707845b217e", "question": "In the game of golf, the iconic \"Green Jacket\" is presented to the winner of which championship?", "answer": "Masters Tournament", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4c46c6c6b019850c9a7b", "question": "In World War II, who was Lyudmila Pavlichenko?", "answer": "Top female Soviet sniper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe767dbeec85e375820b298", "question": "In which US state is Glacier National Park?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d06e21a1c922dd1ac64b1", "question": "Pont Neuf is the oldest bridge over the river Seine, located in which French city?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a2", "question": "What is Ozzy Osbourne's real first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e13806d333868d34d725", "question": "Which African nation successfully resisted colonialism in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a7", "question": "Which artist's \"Impression Sunrise\" gave its name to the whole impressionist movement?", "answer": "Claude Monet's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69c8120565ad31a57c76d", "question": "What was the Old English name for the season after winter?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba2d6874c93a3298b2135", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973d", "question": "For which two movies did Tom Hanks win two consecutive Oscars?", "answer": "Philadelphia and Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b002", "question": "Who was the primary author of the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d6", "question": "What is the only US state with a single syllable name?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc85435abc30a8194e188a6", "question": "George Alan O'Dowd is the birth name for whom?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d76a2596a59cbdfbd3b5", "question": "Which famous work did Thomas Paine write?", "answer": "Common Sense", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980d", "question": "What pop star's first and middle names are Katherine Dawn?", "answer": "KD Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af83", "question": "Which US president asked the US congress to declare war on Japan in 1941?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b851", "question": "In chess, which piece only moves diagonally?", "answer": "The bishop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b554", "question": "In rugby, what is the equivalent of a hockey face-off?", "answer": "Scrum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfbbd9dc5ec6cd98a8317", "question": "What painting is featured prominently in the 2007 film \"St Trinian's\"?", "answer": "Johannes Vermeer's\u00a0\"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6012153c63c99d48cd169ae8", "question": "Which country offered Einstein the presidency?", "answer": "Israel -- Einstein declined, saying he lacked enough of both \"natural aptitude\" and \"experience\" for the role.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911e", "question": "What year did E. M. Forster publish \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "1910", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3c", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69b", "question": "What is the edible part of a sea urchin?", "answer": "The gonads", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcdc", "question": "What common item is usually made up of twelve pentagons and twenty hexagons?", "answer": "A soccer ball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f2", "question": "What sport in the Olympics includes tucks, twists and pikes?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc1e6ec223966ae8f886f", "question": "Who allegedly wrote the song \"Golden Years\" for Elvis Presley but ended up recording it himself?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd4", "question": "What TV show did \"Family Matters\" spin off from?", "answer": "Perfect Strangers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010cab30775fa611bce67fd", "question": "What do the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame and the Louvre have in common?", "answer": "A design by the same architect -- I.M. Pei provided the design for the entrances to both museums.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc1bb6de0eb824d4052e2", "question": "What Islands make up the U.S. Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The U.S. Virgin Islands consist of Saint Croix, Saint Thomas, Saint John, and Water Island, alongside 50 other tiny islets.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43c", "question": "Over which islands did the UK and Argentina fight in 1982?", "answer": "Falkland Islands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b204", "question": "Who was the only US presidential assassin to die in the electric chair?", "answer": "Leon Czolgosz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b6", "question": "Which was the first Space-ready Shuttle to be launched?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c89cf2011619dd6d415481", "question": "Under what name did Eric Cartman appear as a calculus teacher in an inner-city school in season 12 of South Park?", "answer": "Eric Cartmenez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca5", "question": "Who's the only character is \"Peter and the Wolf\" represented by a brass instrument?", "answer": "The wolf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c66", "question": "What comic strip cat was created by Otto Messmer and Pat Sullivan in 1919?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f3", "question": "What fruit was once called a Persian apple?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c674", "question": "Downy, Hairy and Pileated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Woodpecker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d5", "question": "What instrument did Michelle play in American Pie?", "answer": "Flute", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f44a145fb2946670739d", "question": "From which language did the English word \"vampire\" originate?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0b", "question": "What US city is home to the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c471", "question": "What computer programming language is often referred to by coders as \"Camel\"?", "answer": "Perl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f1", "question": "What five tastes can a human distinguish?", "answer": "Sweet, sour, salt, bitter, umami", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9b", "question": "What is the family name of the creator of Tobasco sauce?", "answer": "McIllhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552fd3e1c6f9840ba319f", "question": "Which band released the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22d", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcc", "question": "What TV show did \"Trapper John, M.D.\" spin off from?", "answer": "M*A*S*H", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db74f90ab2c8f322317fe2", "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69c", "question": "Syncope is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7e", "question": "At the beginning of the Spanish-American War, what island did American soldiers invade?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae39", "question": "What Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist was killed during the last months of World War II?", "answer": "Ernie Pyle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339661", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who sold a monorail to the city of Springfield?", "answer": "Lyle Lanley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b665", "question": "What was the first foot product invented by Dr. William Matthias Scholl?", "answer": "Arch supports", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3d", "question": "What slogan did Nancy Reagan create for her drug awareness campaign?", "answer": "Just Say No", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c5d00775fa611bce67cc", "question": "What is the ZIP code for New York City's Empire State Building?", "answer": "10118 -- This zip code applies to occupants of the more than 2.8 million rentable square feet.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2cf8c2596a59cbdfbd370", "question": "Who said, \u201cThe secret of happiness, you see, is not found in seeking more, but in developing the capacity to enjoy less\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb7", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Santa Fe\"?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3eb2c73aa70ea0b70af9", "question": "What was an alternative name for Maryland?", "answer": "Mariana (Lord Baltimore squashed the idea because the name reminded him of Spanish Jesuit and historian Juan de Mariana.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36c", "question": "Laika was the first ever dog to do what?", "answer": "Go into space", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96a", "question": "Gouda and Edam are cities in what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badf", "question": "Which book of the Bible follows Exodus?", "answer": "Leviticus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bd", "question": "Name Dan Hartman's first solo hit?", "answer": "Instant Replay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fc", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80a", "question": "What country controls the Mediterranean island of Corsica?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d9582596a59cbdfbd3c3", "question": "What items did the Stamp Act levy a tax on?", "answer": "Paper products", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd4", "question": "Who was Ronald Reagan's first wife?", "answer": "Jane Wyman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5750c73aa70ea0b70b35", "question": "Which state features the one-word motto \"Excelsior\u201d?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a599", "question": "What old Massachusetts town is nicknamed \"Witch city\"?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d0", "question": "How many guns does Travis buy in the movie \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a74", "question": "Matt Dillon and Kitty Russell were long-running characters on what TV series?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be2", "question": "Ludwig van Beethoven and Francisco Goya both suffered from what ailment?", "answer": "Deafness", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7dc", "question": "Which non-coastal western US state has the seagull as its official state bird?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc1", "question": "What genre is Iggy Pop considered to be the grandfather of?", "answer": "Punk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936d", "question": "For which movie did Humphrey Bogart receive his only Academy Award?", "answer": "The African Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bc", "question": "What natural \"Wonder of the World\" lies off the east coast of Australia?", "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02c", "question": "By marrying Prince Rainier, Grace Kelly became princess of what nation?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c77", "question": "Who wrote the 1955 controversial novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Vladamir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339511", "question": "Which sci-fi movie starred Jane Fonda as \"Queen of the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Barbarella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6e", "question": "At what movie's climax does Mookie throw a garbage can through the front window of Sal's Pizzeria?", "answer": "Do the Right Thing's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeda", "question": "Who commanded the British forces that captured Quebec from the French in 1759?", "answer": "James Wolfe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa96773838c5c8a417f45", "question": "What is a baby kangaroo called?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd660a8a5bfecdd737e0836", "question": "What did \"RMS\" in RMS Titanic stand for?", "answer": "Royal Mail Ship", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c331", "question": "What is brass an alloy of?", "answer": "Copper and zinc", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071e123745b36be73039e1", "question": "What was the name of the first US human spaceflight?", "answer": "Mercury-Redstone 3, aka Freedom 7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994a", "question": "Who played Spiderman's arch\u00ad-nemesis, Green Goblin, in the 2002 Spider- Man movie?", "answer": "Willem Dafoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5952489b736d4be723796b74", "question": "What singer, who went to #1 in 1980 with \"Lookin\u2019 For Love\", published \"Still Lookin\u2019 For Love\", as his autobiography?", "answer": "Johnny Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbdae003d27d341092bc9", "question": "In which state does the Rio Grande begin?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d1", "question": "Which bar is said to have given birth to the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f16516af9b80650dbe7f93c", "question": "Which Mormon founded Salt Lake City?", "answer": "Brigham Young", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d9692596a59cbdfbd3c4", "question": "Who led the covert mission known as the Boston Tea Party?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c080", "question": "People with hypertrichosis have lots of what?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c548", "question": "How wide is the average bolt of lightning?", "answer": "1/2 inch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f090ff048f679a45aa9f", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe908a101dd7bf43be5e886", "question": "What vitamin does E. coli produce?", "answer": "K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae19", "question": "In which decade did Hawaii become a state?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7a", "question": "What did Aristotle claim as the most delicate of table meats?", "answer": "Camel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a820", "question": "What river forms much of the border between Washington and Oregon?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339989", "question": "Who played Mallory Keaton on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e6", "question": "What year was carbon 14 first discovered?", "answer": "1940", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e803cade59ea584496fe9f", "question": "The novel \"The Great Dog Robbery\" is better known under what title?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bd05d3e40191c55fd523fb6", "question": "Who is the archenemy of Spider-Man?", "answer": "Spider-Man doesn't have a single archenemy but a number of them", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda1", "question": "What are the \"ten\" referred to when a surfer \"hangs ten\" on a wave?", "answer": "His ten toes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7360deec85e375820b258", "question": "What was the name of the doctor who treated John Wilkes Booth's fractured leg after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "Dr. Samuel Mudd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f146cee580c7f8fd1e4e", "question": "Who said, \"Well done is better than well said.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c8f30775fa611bce67e6", "question": "\"A capella\" is an Italian term that means what?", "answer": "\"In the manner of the chapel\" --  A capella music is a group or solo performance without instrumental accompaniment.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133932f", "question": "Who shot JR?", "answer": "Kristin Shepard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339434", "question": "Who co-wrote and directed the 1974 movie \"Young Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Mel Brooks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca19", "question": "Toxiphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Being poisoned", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596dffd39616e6c6d4eba500", "question": "The Spanish Civil War began in what year? ", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bb03364247bf200fb89e", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "The Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91c", "question": "In 1968, what became a required part of the automobile's safety equipment in the US?", "answer": "The seat belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c2", "question": "What is Mickey Mouse's dog's name?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b924", "question": "What publication makes weather predictions based on a secret formula developed in 1792?", "answer": "The Old Farmer's Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea434aff048f679a45ab81", "question": "Which type of rhinoceros is the largest on average?", "answer": "White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac99", "question": "Which of the US Presidents was the first to be born in the 20th century?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96b", "question": "What is a pencils lead typically made from?", "answer": "Graphite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600244004be4723ccac2219f", "question": "Snowball and Napoleon are pigs who appear in which George Orwell novel?", "answer": "\"Animal Farm\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab44", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffb161cf6db9ac4808cf4", "question": "Where is the largest natural amphitheater in the U.S.?", "answer": "Los Angeles, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a53690aac110e4167072", "question": "What types of beer are usually used in the making of a Black and Tan?", "answer": "Pale lager and stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c493", "question": "What animal has been dubbed nature's skyscraper?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7d", "question": "Who was the first person to plant a vineyard in the Bible?", "answer": "Noah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c6", "question": "The Great Gazoo was an alien in which cartoon series?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8cc0694b094db9158309c", "question": "What was the category for \u201cBest Picture\u201d named during the 1st Academy Awards in 1929?", "answer": "Outstanding Picture", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e21", "question": "Which character was most seriously injured by the winged monkeys in the film \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Scarecrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb08a71cf631c2414a13b60", "question": "What is singer Fergie\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Stacy Ann Ferguson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81c98d0de9af39e9d4686", "question": "What U.S. president was nicknamed \"Napoleon of the Stump?\"", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb15", "question": "What city was home to the NBA's Jazz before moving to Utah?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae23", "question": "In which decade did the construction of the Trans-Siberian Railroad commence?", "answer": "1890s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9930ebfabb9c85d8a970", "question": "What film starred Rosie O'Donnell, Rita Wilson and Meg Ryan?", "answer": "Sleepless in Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a6", "question": "What gate does the three-headed dog Cerberus guard?", "answer": "The gates to the Underworld", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc83eec223966ae8f8890", "question": "After Andy gets assaulted and beaten, who exacts revenge on the one who perpetrated it in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Captain Bryon Hadley cripples Bogs, the leader of the group that assaults Andy.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d1185a4fea7fe947a22284", "question": "By what name is Lignite often referred to as?", "answer": "Brown coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8adee01dd7bf43be5e780", "question": "What is the only king in a traditional deck of cards without a moustache?", "answer": "King of hearts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0de0dfcbed638185eaa11", "question": "What was the most-visited attraction in the UK in 2017?", "answer": "British Museum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1c", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Norma Shearer and Kirsten Dunst?", "answer": "Marie Antoinette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c89ce0011619dd6d415480", "question": "Under what name did Eric Cartman appear as a calculus teacher in an inner-city school in season 12?", "answer": "Eric Cartmenez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a97", "question": "What 1927 Al Jolson film was remade in 1980 starring Neil Diamond?", "answer": "The Jazz Singer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77ceaf24f0f7a362efd548", "question": "The CN Tower is in which Canadian city?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "593c4b3ab8198b9a2b077961", "question": "The film \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\" was released in which year?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067be0ff9c0647b50a8068", "question": "Who hosted the 88th Academy Awards?", "answer": "Chris Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b875", "question": "What make of car appears in the left foreground of the \"Abbey Road\" cover?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad87", "question": "Who proposed the idea of \"Laissez-faire\"?", "answer": "Adam Smith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f433fa5fdd6dd25324de", "question": "Ornamental railings on a balcony are called what?", "answer": "Balustrade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e99a0ebfabb9c85d8a974", "question": "Whose first wife was actress Jane Wyman?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1694af7c52aae91cc07cf", "question": "Which 1868 novel is often considered the first full length, English language detective novel?", "answer": "The Moonstone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eb069f83302ff91e4649c", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1972 film \"The Godfather\" win?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be21", "question": "George Fox is traditionally called the founder of what religious group?", "answer": "The Quakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77cdd024f0f7a362efd543", "question": "Who was the captain of the Bonhomme Richard in the 18th Century??", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa05", "question": "Which mountain range lies in the north of Spain, west of The Pyrenees?", "answer": "The Cantabrian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe5", "question": "How many people are in each of the crews for the Oxford and Cambridge Boat Race?\u00a0", "answer": "9 including the cox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad95", "question": "What WWII figure was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa550dc73aa70ea0b70b20", "question": "Hastings, England has a distinct May Day festival which is known as what?", "answer": "Jack in the Green", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2b", "question": "Who is Jamie Lee Curtis' mother?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e6a3fe83fe1f2a824bd0", "question": "What was Mary Anning (1799\u20131847) famous for?", "answer": "Collecting fossil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cb", "question": "Who played the role of Dr. Frasier Crane in the TV show \"Frasier\"?", "answer": "Kelsey Grammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b88a01dd7bf43be5e7ec", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road to eat are called what?", "answer": "A wake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008dd47f4f3bc4a292f861f", "question": "When was the last time when the U.S officially declared war?", "answer": "June 5, 1942", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b84", "question": "Who was the first singer to have five #1 singles off of one album?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339292", "question": "Which 1989 movie did Weird Al Yankovic starred in and cowrote?", "answer": "UHF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ff", "question": "What status did astronomers downgrade Pluto to in 2006?", "answer": "Dwarf Planet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4e", "question": "The 1999 Russell Crowe film \"The Insider\" concerned a whistle-blower in what industry?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e62", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Hank Hill?", "answer": "Mike Judge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd7", "question": "What kind of cheese is most commonly sold in the US as processed \"string cheese\"?", "answer": "Mozzarella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c8", "question": "What musical is based on the play \"Pygmalion\"?", "answer": "My Fair Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899ca560d398dc9cf7a6a8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who are Hestia's six siblings?", "answer": "Demeter, Hera, Hades, Zeus, Poseidon, Chiron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9da99e748bb36357acdd4", "question": "What is the largest animal to ever live?", "answer": "The Blue whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c9f811b4e2c7fbd389674f", "question": "What country does Cafe au lait originate from?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae58", "question": "The Minutemen fought during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}]